# **David Morisset**

1 Rowallan Gardens, Glasgow, G11 7LH +44.7703.989.569 dmorisset@gmail.com http://morisset-web.co.uk

# **Profile**

As a motivated and enthusiastic IT professional I have 12 years in system administration and support. From these roles I acquired strong problem solving, organisational skills, and general understanding of IT. In the last few years, I have also invested personal time in learning front-end web technologies. I am aiming to bring my skills and experience to a dynamic web development team.

#### **Skills**

Web development: Proficient in:

- HTML5.

- CS3: Following the SMACSS methodology.

- Responsive websites built using the mobile first approach.

- W3C standards and accessibility.

- Javascript and jQuery.

Working knowledge of:

- Version control : git.

- Sass and Compass.

- gulp, NPM.

- PHP/MySQL.

- graphic design principles.

Other IT skills: - Expert of Mac OS X and Mac OS X server.

- InDepth understanding of TCP/IP, LDAP, http and DNS.

- Microsoft Office for Mac.

- InDesign CS6.

- Digital Assets Management (Elvis 4 from Woodwing)

- Publishing System (Workspace 2 and Asura 12 from One Vision)

- Troubleshooting methodology

Other skills: - Excellent interpersonal skills and communication.

- Solution driven.

<u>Languages</u>: - French: Fluent (Native Language).

- English: Fluent.

# **Professional Experience**

#### April 2015 - Present:

### Personal Development and non-profits, including:

- rodolf-vanthuyne.com A responsive website fully coded with html, css and javascript/jquery, with a

#### custom-built PHP CMS.

- freecodecamp.com: front-end certification program.
- Other projects can be seen on github.com/David-44 and codepen.io/David44/.

#### Freelance Work:

- alpha-clean.co.uk A simple responsive website.
- Regular freelance for TimeInc, for support and upgrades of their Preflight system.

September 2008 – March 2015: Time Inc, London, United Kingdom.

# Magazine & Content Technology Specialist.

- Setup, installation and day to day administration of Elvis, the DAM solution developed by Woodwing.
- Administration of an adverts production workflow. This workflow includes a media planner (MIPPS, bespoke system built by OpenText for Time Inc), a preflight system (OneVision asura 12.5 working on Workspace 2.5) and a publishing platform (Wave2 and InDesign Server).
- Day to day administration of multiple XServes and one XSAN2 system.

April 2007 - August 2008: Button Live Communication, London, United Kingdom.

# **Network Administrator.**

- Ensuring that everything related to Information Technology is working and up-to-date.
- Administrating a heterogeneous Network (Unix, Mac and Windows).
- Troubleshooting various professional (design, finance) Applications.

Sep 2005 - Feb 2007: Apple Computers, Cork, Ireland

## Network and Multimedia Specialist, French and English.

Answering technical questions and providing troubleshooting on all professional products, including server hardware and software and multimedia applications.

Reporting bugs to engineering, assisting them in the resolution.

Dealing with business critical issues for major accounts customers.

Sep 2003 – Sep 2005: Apple Computers, Cork, Ireland

# Technical Support Level 1(5 months), and Level 2 (18 months), French and English

Ensured customer satisfaction by solving complex technical issues unsolved by level 1 agents.

#### Education

Sep 1999 – Sep 2002: Maitrise in Computer Engineering. Equivalent to a degree in Computer

Engineering. Included final year in University of Limerick, Ireland.

Faculté des Sciences et Techniques de Nantes, France.

Modules Included:

Networking, Programming, Algorithmic, Computer Architecture, Artificial Intelligence, Software Design, Databases, Systems.

Sep 1996 – June 1999: Post Leaving Certificate Preparatory Course for Engineer Schools.

Lycée Livet, Nantes, France.

Modules Included:

Mathematics, Physics, Mechanics, Electronics.

Sep 1993 – June 1996: Baccalauréat in Science, Equivalent to Leaving Certificate.

Lycée Livet, Nantes, France.